{
    "id": "bd4a3555aa3843bdac984ddccfbeb971",
    "title": "Subject Verb Agreement",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Time and tide ………………………. for none.",
            "description": "If two nouns together represent one idea or refer to one person or thing, the verb is singular.",
            "answers": [
                "wait",
                "waits"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The state of his affairs ………………………… sure to cause anxiety to his creditors.",
            "description": "Here the real subject is the singular expression ‘state’.",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "My father and I ………………………… soccer.",
            "description": "When two singular subjects are connected by ‘and’, the verb is plural.",
            "answers": [
                "like",
                "likes"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He or his friend …………………………… the secret.",
            "description": "When two singular subjects are connected by or, the verb is singular.",
            "answers": [
                "know",
                "knows"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He or his friends ………………………… responsible for this.",
            "description": "When a singular noun and a plural noun are connected by ‘or’, the verb agrees with the number of the noun closest to it.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Neither my friends nor I …………………………….. interested in this offer.",
            "description": "When we connect two nouns with neither and nor, the verb agrees with the number and person of the noun nearest to it.",
            "answers": [
                "am",
                "are",
                "is"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Either he or you …………………………. mistaken.",
            "description": "When we connect two nouns with either and or, the verb agrees with the number and person of the noun nearest to it.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "am",
                "are"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Oil as well as gas ………………………… imported to India.",
            "description": "When we connect two subjects with as well as, the verb usually agrees with the first subject in number and person.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The mother along with her children ………………………… waiting in the lobby.",
            "description": "When we connect two subjects with ‘along with’, the verb agrees with the first subject in number and person.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Many a man …………………………. lost his life at sea.",
            "description": "We use a singular verb after the expression ‘many a man’.",
            "answers": [
                "has",
                "have"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The Pickwick Papers ……………………….. written by Charles Dickens.",
            "description": "The names of books and magazines are all singular. ",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "None of my shirts ………………………… clean.",
            "description": "None can be followed by a singular or plural verb.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}